<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="info_details">
        <item>"
            This is a basic technique but with effective results. You must inhale for 4 seconds, hold it for 2-3 seconds and then exhale in 6 seconds. You have to make sure that you exhale longer than you inhale. At the beginning it might seem hard to exhale in 6 seconds but if you take full breaths and breath with your diaphragm, it is possible to do so. In the first few tries you might not exhale during the full 6 seconds but as long as you breath consciously the breathing exercise should help to calm you down."</item>
        <item>"
            During a panic attack our mind stays focused on dark thoughts and the feeling of fear, we can no longer correctly perceive what is around us and where we are. Panic overwhelms us. In this kind of situation the best way to achieve a calmer state of mind is to remind yourself of your surroundings, of the physical world.

            This is where technique 5-4-3-2-1 comes into play, as it trains all the 5 senses (sight, touch, hearing, smell and taste) helping you to stay connected with the environment, reminding you of the spaces around you, and it gives the mind something else to think about other than fear.

            How does it work?
5) Name 5 things that you can see
4) Name 4 things that you can touch(actually touch them and concentrate on the different textures)
3) Name 3 things that you can here
2) Name 2 things that you can smell
1) Name 1 things that you can taste(if you can't find anything to taste, think about the last thing you have eaten)
When naming the objects you can either say them out loud or in your head.
"</item>

        <item>"It is a simple four-step mental checklist that helps calm down your brain. It can be done very quick so when you don’t have much time on your hands this is the perfect solution.
Let me present it to you:
            S=Stop
Stop what you are doing: Press the pause button on your thought and actions
            T=Take
Take a few deep breaths to center yourself and bring yourself fully into the present moment
            O=Observe
Observe what is going on with you:
Body
What physical sensations are you aware of (touch, sight, hearing, taste, smell)?
Just a quick check it helps to get your mind of your thoughts on the inside and focus on the outside.
 Emotions
What are you feeling right now?
Just an overview, are you sad, anxious, scared?
         P=Process
Process everything you just felt and/or are still feeling, your body and your emotions. It’s ok to just stay somewhere and process everything.
https://www.themuse.com/advice/the-mental-trick-you-can-use-to-get-through-any-stressful-situation

"</item>

        <item>"
            There are a lot of journaling techniques out there and there aren’t any “right” or “wrong” whatever works for is perfect. By presenting here several of them you can select the one that you think sounds best for you and use it. Depends on the person but you can journal on a notebook or in the notes app or anywhere else where you can just express yourself through writing.
1)	Documentation journal


            Document your attacks and your solutions. This journaling technique can not only help you in the future when you have another attack or when you have to explain to someone exactly what you went through.
You can start slow:
How did you feel at the beginning?
When did you realize that it is a panic attack?
And to the best extent you can remember, what did you feel through the hole experience?
Try to describe it.


2)	Free writing

            Free writing means setting a timer and letting your thoughts flow, unedited and unscripted.
Don’t think just write.
Free writing is all about keeping your hand moving, or fingers typing and not pausing to go back and edit. If you run out of ideas, you just keep writing whatever comes to mind. Whether that’s describing your surroundings or thinking about your grocery list.

How does free writing help?
Free writing is incredibly powerful to unpack a confusing dilemma or make sense of your mixed emotions. It also helps you unlock suppressed emotions you’d otherwise abashedly skip quickly over. But when you’re just looking to fill those pages, you’ll grab on to anything including those pesky feelings you’d normally try to stash away.

Getting things down on paper puts you in touch with your honest, uncensored self.

Tips for free writing:
- start small: aim for a page or 10 minutes of continuous writing
- start with writing about how you’re feeling. Do a brief check-in and write about what’s bothering you and what’s going well. Jot down any worries or anxieties currently on your mind.


3)	Unsent letters

An unsent letter is never meant to be mailed. It’s an incredible journaling technique to help you get closure or find peace of mind.

You don’t necessary have to send it to a real person. You can send it to your past or future self. Or if you find what or who is your trigger and causing your panic attack you can send the letter to them.

You can also write letters as a way to express gratitude to those who’d made a difference in your life, past and present.


4)	One line a day journaling

Writing just a single line a day helps preserve memory and let’s you notice patterns.

Don’t try to capture everything. Just capture a key moment and record even the mundane. What seems ordinary now will soon be a memory you’ll love to reminisce about.

One line a day journaling can help you get into the habit of writing everyday. It’s not too overwhelming to jot down a sentence, so you’ll be more likely to keep at it.

After you write this one line and discover that you are in the mood, no one knows, your sentence might actually turn into a free writing session.

Prompts for one line a day journaling:
•	What’s the best thing that happened to you today?
•	What are you thankful for today?
•	What lesson did you learn today?
•	What was the best thing you ate?
•	Name the person that made you smile
•	Name your biggest task for tomorrow
•	Name the best song you heard today



5)	Gratitude journal


            This is one of the most powerful journaling techniques with life-changing possibilities that’s proven in studies to make a happier and more productive person. It also lower your stress and calms you at night.

A gratitude journal reminds us to stop always striving for more and just appreciate the present.

But don’t rush through it. Write in detail about what you’re thankful for and let yourself feel those emotions and experience the sensations. Diving deep into a few things you’re grateful for is more beneficial that listing off all the blessings you can think of.
Don’t make your gratitude journal another thing to tick off your to-do list. Savor the experience and take your time.

Gratefulness prompts:
•	Write about an old relationship that helped a lot
•	Something good that happened yesterday

 https://vanillapapers.net/2020/08/25/journaling-techniques/

"</item>
        <item>"
            Before starting to present some of the signs and symptoms of panic attacks you have to understand that every person experiences them differenty. So you don't have to check them like you check off you shopping list. You might experience some of them, you might experience others but the main point is that during a panic attack your brain activates the fight or flight mode so you might be scared (of impending doom, of losing cotrol, and so on) but you have to remind yourself that you are safe and it's all happening inside your brain. These reactions happen most of the times because they are triggered by something. To find out more about triggers you should read our "What is your trigger?" paragraph.


            There are more detail there. Now onto physical symptoms: you might experience
• sweating,
•trembling or shaking, •accelerated heart rate, •shortness of breath or •thightness in your throat, •chills,
•hot flashes,
•nausea
•abdominal cramping
•chest pain
•headaches
•dizziness, lightheadedness or faintness
• numbness or tingling sensations
•feelings of unreality or detachment


            One of the worst things about panic attacks is the intense fear that you'll have another one. You may fear having panic attacks so much that you avoid certain situations where they may occur.
"</item>
        <item>"
            More often than not, if you already experienced a panic attack you are more likely to experience one again. That's why you should concentrate yourself on preventing panic attacks as well as making them disappear.

            A very effective way to prevent panic attacks is to choose one of the calming techniques (breathing, square breathing, 5-4-3-2-1 technique, stop technique) and practice it in your free time everyday(only a couple minutes like 3- 5 are enough, the practice doesn't have to be long, just consistent). This trains your nervous system to calm down faster so it the unlikely case that you exercise another panic attack you will overcome it faster.

            We recommend you to focus on prevention other than action as chances are that if you don't try to practice daily, when a new panic attack will come(if it will come) some if the techniques might not longer work.
"</item>
        <item>"
            Panic attacks don’t really come out of nowhere, there might be a reason for way you started having them, usually they’re caused by stress, but they can also be caused by a terrifying event from your past that had a negative effect on you (you felt on the street for example,  now you believe the streets to be a very unsafe place, just the thought of going out triggers the panic inside you).
            A panic attack is when the fear triggers for no reason (your subconscious mind saw something in the outside world that it considers dangerous whiteout a clear reason). When thinking of the trigger you need to think of all the stressful and terrifying events from your past and try to identify which one was the worst,  or after which one the panic attacks started.

            Once you figure out what your trigger is you can start working to overcome it, eliminating panic attacks right from the source.  Even though it sounds easy finding the trigger is very difficult as our subconscious mind doesn’t see all events the way we do, if you need it we recommend you to ask for professional help.
"</item>
        <item>"
            Our app provides you with the best known and most efficient panic calming techniques, but as we are all different people, we have different things that help us, so even if chances are low this metodes might not work for you, or you might experience a very severe panic attack, it this cases you recommend you to call a specialist and ask for professional help."</item>
        <item>"
            https://youtu.be/d0tU18Ybcvk

            https://youtu.be/mPZkdNFkNps

            https://youtu.be/79kpoGF8KWU

            https://youtu.be/FdN1pnEaJs0
"</item>
        <item>"
https://youtu.be/Lp2jgkoVLys
https://youtu.be/4TRuJpSyMoY
https://youtu.be/wR8oKZ5qTfk

https://youtu.be/IzFObkVRSV0

https://youtu.be/GTwTpXINW7I
https://youtu.be/bphhWzXeQKU
https://youtu.be/_nMAJI8-Lzk
https://youtu.be/gnVdXN_iZsQ
https://youtu.be/_clCzEnTvAE
"</item>
        <item>"Here you can find the websites from where we took our information from.

            https://alexandrucretu.wordpress.com/2020/12/08/tehnici-de-relaxare-metoda-5-4-3-2-1/

            https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/panic-attacks/symptoms-causes/syc-20376021
"</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>
